<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recipes on The Open Source Cookbook</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/</link><description>Recent content in Recipes on The Open Source Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BBQ Pork Dry Rub</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/bbq-pork-dry-rub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/bbq-pork-dry-rub/</guid><description>This is a nice Cajun style dry dub for BBQ pork. This is good for about a pound of pork.
Ingredients 1 Tbsp. chili powder 1 1/2 tsp. cumin 1 1/2 tsp. garlic powder 1 1/2 tsp. oregano 3/4 tsp. sea salt 1/2 tsp. black pepper 1/4 tsp. cinnamon Directions Whisk all of the ingredients in a bowl Coat pork thoroughly Store pork in a air tight container at room temperature until ready to cook, but obviously no longer than a few hours BBQ the pork</description></item><item><title>Vegan Quinoa Chili</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/vegan-quinoa-chili/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/vegan-quinoa-chili/</guid><description>I spent a couple of years practicing a vegetarian diet. This was my favorite take away from that era.
Ingredients 1 container (2 1/2 cup 125mls ea.), Chick Peas 1 tablespoon, Oil - Olive 1 small, Onions - Raw 3 clove, Garlic - Raw 1 pepper, Peppers - Jalapeno, raw 1 large (7-1/4&amp;quot; to 8-1/2&amp;quot; long), Carrots - Raw 2 stalk large (11&amp;quot;-12&amp;quot; long), Celery - Raw 1 medium (8oz), Green Bell Pepper 1 pepper, Red Bell Pepper 1 cup, chopped, Squash - Zucchini, includes skin, raw 2 cup, Beans - Kidney, canned 2 cup, Organic Black Beans Canned 2 cup, Canned Diced Tomatoes 2 cup, Tomato Sauce - Crushed Tomatoes 3 tbsp, Spices - Chili powder 1 tsp, Ground Cumin 0.</description></item><item><title>Potato Salad</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/potato-salad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/potato-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients 4 russet potatoes 5 eggs 1/2 cup pickle juice 2 pickles Green onion 1 tbsp mustard 1/2 cup mayo 1 tbsp dill weed 1 clove of minced garlic Bacon (optional) Directions Boil your eggs Place them in a pot of water, bring them to a boil Once at a full boil, turn off the element and wait 10 minutes Douse eggs in cold water and let them cool Cook your optional bacon Peel your potatoes and chop them into 1 inch halves or quarters Put the potatoes in a large pot with a generous amount of water to submerge them Boil the potatoes until the soften.</description></item><item><title>Greek Seasoning</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/greek-seasoning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/greek-seasoning/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 teaspoons salt 2 teaspoons garlic powder 2 teaspoons Greek oregano 2 teaspoons dried basil 1 teaspoon dried onion 1 teaspoon ground black pepper 1 teaspoon dried parsley 1 teaspoon dried dill weed 1 teaspoon dried marjoram 1/2 teaspoon ground thyme 1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon ground nutmeg Directions Combine all ingredients together in a bowl and store in an airtight container for up to one month. For a smoother texture, you can purée all ingredients for 30-45 seconds in a food processor or use a spice grinder.</description></item><item><title>Terragon Chicken</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/terragon-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/terragon-chicken/</guid><description>This recipe comes from my aunt-in-law, Kay. My wife had it at her home on a trip up-island while I was stuck at home looking after the dog. My wife raved about it :)
Kay did call for a specific brand of Greek seasoning. I chose to separate that into its material components to make it simpler to prepare. If you can find &amp;ldquo;Cavender&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; all purpose Greek seasoning, use that.</description></item><item><title>Yummy Dressing</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/yummy-dressing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/yummy-dressing/</guid><description>This dressing is easy and plentiful. You get about 2 litres of dressing to work with. It keeps really well in the fridge.
Definitely cut back this recipe if the quantity is too much.
Ingredients 1 cup nutritional yeast 1/3 cup soy sauce 1/3 cup apple cider vinegar 1/3 cup water 2-3 cloves crushed garlic 2 cups of vegetable oil (canola, olive, whatever) Directions Throw everything into a blender except for the vegetable oil.</description></item><item><title>Mexican Bean Salad</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/mexican-bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/mexican-bean-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (15 ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained 1 (15 ounce) can kidney beans, rinsed and drained 1 (15 ounce) can cannellini beans, rinsed and drained 1 green bell pepper, chopped 1 red bell pepper, chopped 1 (10 ounce) package frozen corn kernels, thawed 1 red onion, diced 1/2 cup olive oil 1/2 cup red wine vinegar 1/4 cup chopped fresh cilantro 2 tablespoons fresh lime juice 1 tablespoon lemon juice 1 clove garlic, crushed 2 tablespoons white sugar 1 tablespoon salt 1 1/2 teaspoons ground cumin 1 1/2 teaspoons ground black pepper 1/2 teaspoon chili powder, or to taste 1 dash hot pepper sauce, or to taste Directions Combine beans, bell peppers, corn, and red onion in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Cachew Chicken</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/cachew-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/cachew-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 raw chicken thighs (boneless, skinless) 2 tbsp coconut oil(for cooking) 1/4 cup raw cashews 1/2 medium Green Bell Pepper 1/2 tsp ground ginger 1 tbsp rice wine vinegar 1 1/2 tbsp liquid aminos 1/2 tbsp chili garlic sauce 1 tbsp minced garlic 1 tbsp Sesame Oil 1 tbsp Sesame Seeds 1 tbsp green onions 1/4 medium white onion Salt + Pepper Directions Heat a pan over low heat and toast the cashews for 8 minutes or until they start to lightly brown and become fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Dill Pickles</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/dill-pickles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/dill-pickles/</guid><description>Equipment Chef&amp;rsquo;s knife Cutting board 2 wide-mouth pint jars with lids Large pot, if canning Ingredients 1 1/2 pounds Kirby or Persian cucumbers 4 cloves garlic, peeled and smashed 2 teaspoons dill seeds 1/2 teaspoon red pepper flakes (optional) 1 cup apple cider vinegar (or white vinegar) 1 cup water 1 1/2 tablespoons pickling salt or kosher salt Directions Prepare the jars. If you are planning to can your pickles for long-term storage, bring a large pot of water to a boil and sterilize 2 wide-mouth pint jars and their lids.</description></item><item><title>Quick and Easy Chicken Noodle Soup</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/quick-and-easy-chicken-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/quick-and-easy-chicken-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tablespoon butter 1/2 cup chopped onion 1/2 cup chopped celery 4 (14.5 ounce) cans chicken broth 1 (14.5 ounce) can vegetable broth 1/2 pound chopped cooked chicken breast 1 1/2 cups egg noodles 1 cup sliced carrots 1/2 teaspoon dried basil 1/2 teaspoon dried oregano salt and ground black pepper to taste Directions Melt butter in a large pot over medium heat. Add onion and celery and cook until just tender, about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Butter Chicken</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/butter-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/butter-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients Some basmati or white along with the stuff required to make the Marinade and Curry.
Marinade 1/2 cup plain yoghurt, full fat 1 tbsp lemon juice 1 tsp tumeric powder 2 tsp garam masala (Note 1) 1/2 tsp chilli powder or cayenne pepper powder (Note 2) 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tbsp ginger, freshly grated 2 cloves garlic, crushed 1.5 lb / 750 g chicken thigh fillets, cut into bite size pieces Curry 2 tbsp (30 g) ghee or butter, OR 1 tbsp vegetable oil (Note 3) 1 cup tomato passata (aka tomato puree) (Note 4) 1 cup heavy / thickened cream (Note 5) 1 tbsp sugar 1 1/4 tsp salt Directions Optional blitz: for an extra smooth sauce, combine the Marinade ingredients (except the chicken) in a food processor and blend until smooth.</description></item><item><title>Easy Coleslaw Dressing</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-coleslaw-dressing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-coleslaw-dressing/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 cup mayonnaise 2 tablespoons white sugar 1 1/2 tablespoons lemon juice 1 tablespoon vinegar 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 1/4 teaspoon salt Directions Whisk mayonnaise, sugar, lemon juice, vinegar, pepper, and salt together in a bowl until smooth and creamy.</description></item><item><title>Slow Cooker Beef Stew</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/slow-cooker-beef-stew/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/slow-cooker-beef-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 pounds beef stew meat, cut into 1-inch pieces 1/4 cup all-purpose flour 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 1 1/2 cups beef broth 4 medium carrots, sliced 3 medium potatoes, diced 1 medium onion, chopped 1 stalk celery, chopped 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce 1 teaspoon ground paprika 1 clove garlic, minced 1 large bay leaf Directions Place meat in slow cooker. Mix flour, salt, and pepper together in a small bowl.</description></item><item><title>Mustard Vinaigrette</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/mustard-vinaigrette/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/mustard-vinaigrette/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 cup white vinegar 1 tablespoon honey 1 tablespoon prepared Dijon-style mustard 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 2 teaspoons salt 2 teaspoons minced garlic 1 cup vegetable oil 4 drops hot sauce Directions In a small bowl, whisk together the vinegar, honey, mustard, pepper, salt, garlic, oil and hot sauce until thoroughly combined. Chill until serving.</description></item><item><title>Corn Bread</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/corn-bread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/corn-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup of cornmeal 3/4 cup of all-purpose flour 2-4 tablespoons of sugar 2 1/2 teaspoons of baking powder 1/2 teaspoon of salt 1 cup of milk 2 eggs 1/4 cup of butter, melted Directions Preheat oven to 400°F. Grease an 8x8x2-inch square or 9x1 1/2-inch round baking pan; set aside. In a medium bowl stir together cornmeal, flour, sugar, baking powder, and salt; set aside. In a small bowl whisk together the milk, eggs, and butter.</description></item><item><title>Guacamole</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/guacamole/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 avocados - peeled, pitted, and mashed 1 lime, juiced 1 teaspoon salt 1/2 cup diced onion 3 tablespoons chopped fresh cilantro 2 roma (plum) tomatoes, diced 1 teaspoon minced garlic 1 pinch ground cayenne pepper Directions In a medium bowl, mash together the avocados, lime juice, and salt. Mix in onion, cilantro, tomatoes, and garlic. Stir in cayenne pepper. Refrigerate 1 hour for best flavor, or serve immediately.</description></item><item><title>Beef Stroganoff III</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-stroganoff-iii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-stroganoff-iii/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 pounds beef chuck roast 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 4 ounces butter 4 green onions, sliced (white parts only) 4 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1 (10.5 ounce - 300ml) can condensed beef broth 1 teaspoon prepared mustard 1 (6 ounce) can sliced mushrooms, drained 1/3 cup sour cream 1/3 cup white wine Directions Remove any fat and gristle from the roast and cut into strips 1/2 inch thick by 2 inches long.</description></item><item><title>Angel Food Cake</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/angel-food-cake/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 18:19:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/angel-food-cake/</guid><description>Figure 1: A lovely angelfood cake. Probably not what mine will look like.
Ingredients 1-1/2 cups egg whites (about 10) 3/4 cup plus 1/2 cup sugar, divided 1/4 cup cornstarch 1/4 cup white rice flour 1/4 cup tapioca flour 1/4 cup potato starch 1-1/2 teaspoons cream of tartar 3/4 teaspoon salt 3/4 teaspoon vanilla extract Assorted fresh fruit, optional Directions Place egg whites in a large bowl; let stand at room temperature for 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Asian Lettuce Wraps</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/asian-lettuce-wraps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/asian-lettuce-wraps/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 tsp olive oil, divided 1 lb 93% lean ground turkey or chicken 4 - 5 Tbsp hoisin sauce to taste 1 Tbsp wheat free tamari 2 tsp sriracha (optional) 1 Tbsp rice vinegar 1 1/2 tsp sesame oil 1 tsp honey (optional) 1 Tbsp minced fresh garlic (3 cloves) 1 Tbsp peeled and minced fresh ginger 2/3 cup sliced green onions, white and light green portion, plus more green portion for serving 1 medium carrot, peeled and shredded (1/2 cup) 1 (8 oz) can water chestnuts, drained and chopped small 1 large head Bibb lettuce or iceberg lettuce Directions Heat 1 1/2 tsp oil in a 12-inch non-stick skillet over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>BBQ Teriyaki Pork Kabobs</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/bbq-teriyaki-pork-kabobs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/bbq-teriyaki-pork-kabobs/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 tablespoons wheat-free tamari 3 tablespoons olive oil 1 clove garlic, minced 1/2 teaspoon crushed red pepper flakes salt and pepper to taste 1 pound boneless pork loin, cut into 1 inch cubes 1 (14.5 ounce) can low-sodium beef broth 2 tablespoons cornstarch 2 tablespoons wheat free tamari 1 tablespoon brown sugar 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/4 teaspoon ground ginger 3 portobello mushrooms, cut into quarters 1 large red onion, cut into 12 wedges 12 cherry tomatoes 12 bite-size chunks fresh pineapple Directions In a shallow dish, mix together 3 tablespoons tamari, olive oil, 1 clove minced garlic, red pepper flakes, salt, and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Beef Shish Kebabs for Freezer Cooking</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-shish-kebabs-for-freezer-cooking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-shish-kebabs-for-freezer-cooking/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 zucchini, cut into chunks 1 red bell pepper, cut into 1 inch pieces 1 (15 ounce) can pineapple chunks, drained 2 tablespoons olive oil ½ cup ketchup 1 teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons steak sauce 2 tablespoons white sugar 2 tablespoons apple cider vinegar 2 tablespoons worcestershire sauce ¼ cup water 1 ½ pounds beef sirloin, cut into 1 inch cubes 12 bamboo skewers Directions Place the zucchini, bell pepper, and pineapple in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Steak Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/steak-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/steak-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients Try with Tamarind 1 1/4 cups ketchup 2 tablespoons prepared yellow mustard 3 tablespoons worcestershire sauce 1 1/2 tablespoons apple cider vinegar 4 drops hot pepper sauce (e.g. Tabasco) 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper Directions In a medium bowl, mix together the ketchup, mustard, Worcestershire sauce, vinegar, hot pepper sauce, salt and pepper. Transfer to a jar and refrigerate until needed.</description></item><item><title>Easy Pizza Sauce I</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-pizza-sauce-i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-pizza-sauce-i/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (6 ounce) can tomato paste 1 1/2 cups water 1/3 cup extra virgin olive oil 2 cloves garlic, minced salt to taste ground black pepper to taste 1/2 tablespoon dried oregano 1/2 tablespoon dried basil 1/2 teaspoon dried rosemary, crushed Directions Mix together the tomato paste, water, and olive oil. Mix well. Add garlic, salt and pepper to taste, oregano, basil, and rosemary. Mix well and let stand several hours to let flavors blend.</description></item><item><title>Homemade Hoisin Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/homemade-hoisin-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/homemade-hoisin-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/4 cup wheat free tamari 2 tablespoons smooth peanut butter 1 tablespoon dark brown sugar 2 teaspoons rice wine vinegar 2 teaspoons sesame oil 1 teaspoon hot sauce, or to taste 1 clove garlic, minced 1/8 teaspoon ground black pepper Directions Whisk tamari, peanut butter, brown sugar, rice wine vinegar, sesame oil, hot sauce, garlic, and black pepper together in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Ultra Juicy Grilled BBQ Pork Chops</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/ultra-juicy-grilled-bbq-pork-chops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/ultra-juicy-grilled-bbq-pork-chops/</guid><description>Ingredients 4-6 thick-cut boneless pork chops salt and pepper 1 cup ketchup 2/3 cup brown sugar - packed Try half this amount for a healther sauce. Still delicious 3 tablespoons worcestershire sauce 3 tablespoons apple cider vinegar 2 tablespoons dijon mustard 1 teaspoon mesquite seasoning - see note 1/2 teaspoon garlic powder 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon cracked black pepper - if using ground pepper, reduce to 1/8 teaspoon Directions In a medium sauce pan over medium heat, combine all ingredients for the bbq sauce.</description></item><item><title>Banana Pancakes</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/banana-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/banana-pancakes/</guid><description>One of my absolute favorite recipes. It was discovered, and altered by my wife. I enjoy them most with peanut butter and warm berries that were heated from frozen. Try them with any toppings you&amp;rsquo;d like.
Ingredients 4 mashed bananas. 5 if you&amp;rsquo;re extra. 2 tsp vanilla 4 eggs 3 tsp baking powder 3/4 cup flour 1 tbsp of butter per pan. Directions Peel and thoroughly mash the bananas into a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Easy Slow Cooker Ham</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-slow-cooker-ham/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-slow-cooker-ham/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (6 pound) bone-in country ham 30 whole cloves 3 cups apple cider, or as needed 1 cup brown sugar 1 cup maple syrup 2 tablespoons ground cinnamon 1 tablespoon ground nutmeg 2 teaspoons ground ginger 2 tablespoons ground cloves 1 tablespoon vanilla extract 1 orange&amp;rsquo;s peel Directions Press whole cloves into the ham so they are evenly distributed. You may score the ham for easier insertion if you wish.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Dipping Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/peanut-dipping-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/peanut-dipping-sauce/</guid><description>My family goes nuts for this peanut sauce. Pun intended. It is probably the strong driver of Asian inspired meals in my home.
Ingredients 3/4 cup creamy peanut butter 1/4 cup rice vinegar 1/3 cup wheat-free tamari 3 tablespoons honey 1 1/2 teaspoons grated fresh ginger or 1/2 teaspoon ground ginger 1 to 2 medium cloves garlic, pressed or minced, to taste 1/4 teaspoon red pepper flakes, plus more for sprinkling 2 to 4 tablespoons water or coconut milk, or as necessary to reach your desired consistency Optional garnishes: sprinkling of chopped roasted peanuts and additional red pepper flakes Directions In a 2-cup liquid measuring cup or medium-sized mixing bowl, whisk together the ingredients until well blended.</description></item><item><title>Roasted Spachcock Chicken</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/roasted-spachcock-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/roasted-spachcock-chicken/</guid><description>This is a really simple way to feed a lot of guests, or have a lot of leftovers. Baked or roasted chicken is delicious. This recipe works well for a barbeque or oven-roasting.
It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that this roasting and seasoning techiques work well for simple cuts of chicken such as breast, or thighs. I just enjoy doing a whole chicken as you get a lot of meat for the same effort.</description></item><item><title>Spachcock Chicken</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/spachcock-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/spachcock-chicken/</guid><description>This is a really simple way to feed a lot of guests, or have a lot of leftovers. Baked or roasted chicken is delicious. This recipe works well for a barbeque or oven-roasting.
It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that this roasting and seasoning techiques work well for simple cuts of chicken such as breast, or thighs. I just enjoy doing a whole chicken as you get a lot of meat for the same effort.</description></item><item><title>Falafel</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/falafel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/falafel/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb dry chickpeas (also known as garbanzo beans). You must start with dry, do NOT substitute canned, they will not work! 1/2 tsp baking soda 1 small onion, roughly chopped 1/4 cup chopped fresh parsley 3-5 cloves garlic (I prefer roasted garlic cloves) 1 1/2 tbsp flour or chickpea flour 1 3/4 tsp salt 2 tsp cumin 1 tsp ground coriander 1/4 tsp black pepper 1/4 tsp cayenne pepper Pinch of ground cardamom 1 tsp baking powder (optional - makes the falafel more fluffy) Vegetable oil for frying - grapeseed, sunflower, avocado, canola, and peanut oils all work well Directions One day ahead: Pour the chickpeas into a large bowl and cover them by about 3 inches of cold water.</description></item><item><title>Worchestershire Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/worchestershire-sauce/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/worchestershire-sauce/</guid><description>Need a solution for seasoning red meat that won&amp;rsquo;t hurt a celiac person? Look no further than here.
Ingredients 1/2 cup apple cider vinegar 2 Tbsp wheat-free tamari 2 Tbsp water 1 Tbsp brown sugar 1/4 tsp ground ginger 1/4 tsp dry mustard 1/4 tsp onion powder 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1/8 tsp cinnamon 1/8 tsp pepper Directions Place all ingredients in a medium saucepan and stir. Bring to a boil, stirring constantly.</description></item><item><title>Butternut Squash Soup</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/butternut-squash-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/butternut-squash-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons butter 1 small onion, chopped 1 stalk celery, chopped 1 medium carrot, chopped 2 medium potatoes, cubed 1 medium butternut squash - peeled, seeded, and cubed 1 (32 fluid ounce) container chicken stock salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste Directions Melt butter in a large pot over medium heat, and cook onion, celery, carrot, potatoes, and squash until lightly browned, about 5 minutes. Pour in enough of the chicken stock to cover vegetables.</description></item><item><title>Crustless Mushroom Spinach Pie</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/crustless-mushroom-spinach-pie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/crustless-mushroom-spinach-pie/</guid><description>Ingredients 8 ounces mushrooms 1 teaspoon minced garlic 2 teaspoon olive oil 10 ounce frozen spinach 2 tablespoons grated parmesan 4 eggs 16 ounces cottage cheese 4% 1/2 cup heavy cream 1 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon pepper 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg 1/2 cup shredded mozzarella Directions Preheat oven to 350 degrees. Thaw frozen spinach and drain, squeeze out as much water as possible. Set aside. Thinly slice mushrooms. Heat oil and garlic in a large skillet.</description></item><item><title>Lentil Stew</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/lentil-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/lentil-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup of lentils 3 cups of water 2 stalks, Celery 1 cup, pieces or slices, Mushrooms - Raw 1 teaspoon, Genetic Table Salt 1 sprinkle, Black Pepper, Ground 1 tbsp, Sirracha 1 cup 123 g, Chickpea Canned 3 tomatoes, chopped 1 potato, Medium Russet Potato 1.50 cup, chopped, Carrots - Raw 2 tbsp vegetable oil Directions Put the water and the lentils in a pot. Chop up onions, carrots, potatoes &amp;amp; mushrooms then and add them to the pot.</description></item></channel></rss>