<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The open source cookbook on The Open Source Cookbook</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/</link><description>Recent content in The open source cookbook on The Open Source Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Easy Pizza Sauce I</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-pizza-sauce-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-pizza-sauce-i/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (6 ounce) can tomato paste 1 1/2 cups water 1/3 cup extra virgin olive oil 2 cloves garlic, minced salt to taste ground black pepper to taste 1/2 tablespoon dried oregano 1/2 tablespoon dried basil 1/2 teaspoon dried rosemary, crushed Directions Mix together the tomato paste, water, and olive oil. Mix well. Add garlic, salt and pepper to taste, oregano, basil, and rosemary. Mix well and let stand several hours to let flavors blend.</description></item><item><title>Homemade Hoisin Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/homemade-hoisin-sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/homemade-hoisin-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/4 cup soy sauce 2 tablespoons smooth peanut butter 1 tablespoon dark brown sugar 2 teaspoons rice wine vinegar 2 teaspoons sesame oil 1 teaspoon hot sauce, or to taste 1 clove garlic, minced 1/8 teaspoon ground black pepper Directions Whisk soy sauce, peanut butter, brown sugar, rice wine vinegar, sesame oil, hot sauce, garlic, and black pepper together in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Dipping Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/peanut-dipping-sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/peanut-dipping-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 3/4 cup creamy peanut butter 1/4 cup rice vinegar 1/3 cup reduced sodium tamari or reduced-sodium soy sauce 3 tablespoons honey 1 1/2 teaspoons grated fresh ginger or 1/2 teaspoon ground ginger 1 to 2 medium cloves garlic, pressed or minced, to taste 1/4 teaspoon red pepper flakes, plus more for sprinkling 2 to 4 tablespoons water or coconut milk, or as necessary to reach your desired consistency Optional garnishes: sprinkling of chopped roasted peanuts and additional red pepper flakes Directions In a 2-cup liquid measuring cup or medium-sized mixing bowl, whisk together the ingredients until well blended.</description></item><item><title>Steak Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/steak-sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/steak-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients Try with Tamarind 1 1/4 cups ketchup 2 tablespoons prepared yellow mustard 3 tablespoons Worcestershire sauce 1 1/2 tablespoons apple cider vinegar 4 drops hot pepper sauce (e.g. Tabasco) 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper Directions In a medium bowl, mix together the ketchup, mustard, Worcestershire sauce, vinegar, hot pepper sauce, salt and pepper. Transfer to a jar and refrigerate until needed.</description></item><item><title>Worchestershire Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/worchestershire-sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/worchestershire-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 cup apple cider vinegar 2 Tbsp GF soy sauce 2 Tbsp water 1 Tbsp brown sugar 1/4 tsp ground ginger 1/4 tsp dry mustard 1/4 tsp onion powder 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1/8 tsp cinnamon 1/8 tsp pepper Directions Place all ingredients in a medium saucepan and stir. Bring to a boil, stirring constantly. Simmer 1 minute. Cool. Pour into a bottle and store in the refrigerator.</description></item><item><title>Butternut Squash Soup</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/butternut-squash-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/butternut-squash-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons butter 1 small onion, chopped 1 stalk celery, chopped 1 medium carrot, chopped 2 medium potatoes, cubed 1 medium butternut squash - peeled, seeded, and cubed 1 (32 fluid ounce) container chicken stock salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste Directions Melt butter in a large pot over medium heat, and cook onion, celery, carrot, potatoes, and squash until lightly browned, about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Lentil Stew</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/lentil-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/lentil-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup of lentils 3 cups of water 369 g, Tomato, Medium Whole (2-3/5&amp;quot; Dia), Raw 2 stalks, Celery 1 cup, pieces or slices, Mushrooms - Raw 1 teaspoon, Genetic Table Salt 1 sprinkle, Black Pepper, Ground 1 tbsp, Sirracha 1 cup 123 g, Chickpea Canned 3 potato, Medium Russet Potato 1.50 cup, chopped, Carrots - Raw 2 tbsp vegetable oil Directions Put the water and the lentils in a pot.</description></item><item><title>Quick and Easy Chicken Noodle Soup</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/quick-and-easy-chicken-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/quick-and-easy-chicken-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tablespoon butter 1/2 cup chopped onion 1/2 cup chopped celery 4 (14.5 ounce) cans chicken broth 1 (14.5 ounce) can vegetable broth 1/2 pound chopped cooked chicken breast 1 1/2 cups egg noodles 1 cup sliced carrots 1/2 teaspoon dried basil 1/2 teaspoon dried oregano salt and ground black pepper to taste Directions Melt butter in a large pot over medium heat. Add onion and celery and cook until just tender, about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Slow Cooker Beef Stew</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/slow-cooker-beef-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/slow-cooker-beef-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 pounds beef stew meat, cut into 1-inch pieces 1/4 cup all-purpose flour 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 1 1/2 cups beef broth 4 medium carrots, sliced 3 medium potatoes, diced 1 medium onion, chopped 1 stalk celery, chopped 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce 1 teaspoon ground paprika 1 clove garlic, minced 1 large bay leaf Directions Place meat in slow cooker. Mix flour, salt, and pepper together in a small bowl.</description></item><item><title>Corn Bread</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/corn-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/corn-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup of cornmeal 3/4 cup of all-purpose flour 2-4 tablespoons of sugar 2 1/2 teaspoons of baking powder 1/2 teaspoon of salt 1 cup of milk 2 eggs 1/4 cup of butter, melted Directions Preheat oven to 400°F. Grease an 8x8x2-inch square or 9x1 1/2-inch round baking pan; set aside. In a medium bowl stir together cornmeal, flour, sugar, baking powder, and salt; set aside. In a small bowl whisk together the milk, eggs, and butter.</description></item><item><title>Falafel</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/falafel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/falafel/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb dry chickpeas (also known as garbanzo beans). You must start with dry, do NOT substitute canned, they will not work! 1/2 tsp baking soda 1 small onion, roughly chopped 1/4 cup chopped fresh parsley 3-5 cloves garlic (I prefer roasted garlic cloves) 1 1/2 tbsp flour or chickpea flour 1 3/4 tsp salt 2 tsp cumin 1 tsp ground coriander 1/4 tsp black pepper 1/4 tsp cayenne pepper Pinch of ground cardamom 1 tsp baking powder (optional - makes the falafel more fluffy) Vegetable oil for frying - grapeseed, sunflower, avocado, canola, and peanut oils all work well Directions One day ahead: Pour the chickpeas into a large bowl and cover them by about 3 inches of cold water.</description></item><item><title>Guacamole</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/guacamole/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 avocados - peeled, pitted, and mashed 1 lime, juiced 1 teaspoon salt 1/2 cup diced onion 3 tablespoons chopped fresh cilantro 2 roma (plum) tomatoes, diced 1 teaspoon minced garlic 1 pinch ground cayenne pepper Directions In a medium bowl, mash together the avocados, lime juice, and salt. Mix in onion, cilantro, tomatoes, and garlic. Stir in cayenne pepper. Refrigerate 1 hour for best flavor, or serve immediately.</description></item><item><title>Ultra Juicy Grilled BBQ Pork Chops</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/ultra-juicy-grilled-bbq-pork-chops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/ultra-juicy-grilled-bbq-pork-chops/</guid><description>Ingredients 4-6 thick-cut boneless pork chops salt and pepper 1 cup ketchup 2/3 cup brown sugar - packed Try half this amount for a healther sauce. Still delicious 3 tablespoons worcestershire sauce 3 tablespoons apple cider vinegar 2 tablespoons dijon mustard 1 teaspoon mesquite seasoning - see note 1/2 teaspoon garlic powder 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon cracked black pepper - if using ground pepper, reduce to 1/8 teaspoon Directions In a medium sauce pan over medium heat, combine all ingredients for the bbq sauce.</description></item><item><title>BBQ Teriyaki Pork Kabobs</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/bbq-teriyaki-pork-kabobs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/bbq-teriyaki-pork-kabobs/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 tablespoons soy sauce 3 tablespoons olive oil 1 clove garlic, minced 1/2 teaspoon crushed red pepper flakes salt and pepper to taste 1 pound boneless pork loin, cut into 1 inch cubes 1 (14.5 ounce) can low-sodium beef broth 2 tablespoons cornstarch 2 tablespoons soy sauce 1 tablespoon brown sugar 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/4 teaspoon ground ginger 3 portobello mushrooms, cut into quarters 1 large red onion, cut into 12 wedges 12 cherry tomatoes 12 bite-size chunks fresh pineapple Directions In a shallow dish, mix together 3 tablespoons soy sauce, olive oil, 1 clove minced garlic, red pepper flakes, salt, and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Beef Shish Kebabs for Freezer Cooking</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-shish-kebabs-for-freezer-cooking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-shish-kebabs-for-freezer-cooking/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 zucchini, cut into chunks 1 red bell pepper, cut into 1 inch pieces 1 (15 ounce) can pineapple chunks, drained 2 tablespoons olive oil ½ cup ketchup 1 teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons steak sauce (such as A1®) 2 tablespoons white sugar 2 tablespoons apple cider vinegar 2 tablespoons Worcestershire sauce ¼ cup water 1 ½ pounds beef sirloin, cut into 1 inch cubes 12 bamboo skewers Directions Place the zucchini, bell pepper, and pineapple in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Beef Stroganoff III</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-stroganoff-iii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/beef-stroganoff-iii/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 pounds beef chuck roast 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 4 ounces butter 4 green onions, sliced (white parts only) 4 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1 (10.5 ounce - 300ml) can condensed beef broth 1 teaspoon prepared mustard 1 (6 ounce) can sliced mushrooms, drained 1/3 cup sour cream 1/3 cup white wine salt to taste ground black pepper to taste Directions Remove any fat and gristle from the roast and cut into strips 1/2 inch thick by 2 inches long.</description></item><item><title>Crustless Mushroom Spinach Pie</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/crustless-mushroom-spinach-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/crustless-mushroom-spinach-pie/</guid><description>Ingredients 8 ounces mushrooms 1 teaspoon minced garlic 2 teaspoon olive oil 10 ounce frozen spinach 2 tablespoons grated parmesan 4 eggs 16 ounces cottage cheese 4% 1/2 cup heavy cream 1 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon pepper 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg 1/2 cup shredded mozzarella Directions Preheat oven to 350 degrees. Thaw frozen spinach and drain, squeeze out as much water as possible. Set aside. Thinly slice mushrooms. Heat oil and garlic in a large skillet.</description></item><item><title>Easy Slow Cooker Ham</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-slow-cooker-ham/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-slow-cooker-ham/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (6 pound) bone-in country ham 30 whole cloves 3 cups apple cider, or as needed 1 cup brown sugar 1 cup maple syrup 2 tablespoons ground cinnamon 1 tablespoon ground nutmeg 2 teaspoons ground ginger 2 tablespoons ground cloves 1 tablespoon vanilla extract 1 orange&amp;rsquo;s peel Directions Press whole cloves into the ham so they are evenly distributed. You may score the ham for easier insertion if you wish.</description></item><item><title>Asian Lettuce Wraps</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/asian-lettuce-wraps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/asian-lettuce-wraps/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 tsp olive oil, divided 1 lb 93% lean ground turkey or chicken 4 - 5 Tbsp hoisin sauce to taste 1 Tbsp wheat free tamari 2 tsp sriracha (optional) 1 Tbsp rice vinegar 1 1/2 tsp sesame oil 1 tsp honey (optional) 1 Tbsp minced fresh garlic (3 cloves) 1 Tbsp peeled and minced fresh ginger 2/3 cup sliced green onions, white and light green portion, plus more green portion for serving 1 medium carrot, peeled and shredded (1/2 cup) 1 (8 oz) can water chestnuts, drained and chopped small 1 large head Bibb lettuce or iceberg lettuce Directions Heat 1 1/2 tsp oil in a 12-inch non-stick skillet over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Banana Pancakes</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/banana-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/banana-pancakes/</guid><description>One of my absolute favorite recipes. It was discovered, and altered by my wife. I enjoy them most with peanut butter and warm berries that were heated from frozen. Try them with any toppings you&amp;rsquo;d like.
Ingredients 4 mashed bananas. 5 if you&amp;rsquo;re extra. 2 tsp vanilla 4 eggs 3 tsp baking powder 3/4 cup flour 1 tbsp of butter per pan. Directions Peel and thoroughly mash the bananas into a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Mustard Vinaigrette</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/mustard-vinaigrette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:03:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/mustard-vinaigrette/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 cup white vinegar 1 tablespoon honey 1 tablespoon prepared Dijon-style mustard 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 2 teaspoons salt 2 teaspoons minced garlic 1 cup vegetable oil 4 drops hot sauce Directions In a small bowl, whisk together the vinegar, honey, mustard, pepper, salt, garlic, oil and hot sauce until thoroughly combined. Chill until serving.</description></item><item><title>Angel Food Cake</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/angel-food-cake/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/angel-food-cake/</guid><description>Figure 1: A lovely angelfood cake. Probably not what mine will look like.
Ingredients 1-1/2 cups egg whites (about 10) 3/4 cup plus 1/2 cup sugar, divided 1/4 cup cornstarch 1/4 cup white rice flour 1/4 cup tapioca flour 1/4 cup potato starch 1-1/2 teaspoons cream of tartar 3/4 teaspoon salt 3/4 teaspoon vanilla extract Assorted fresh fruit, optional Directions Place egg whites in a large bowl; let stand at room temperature for 30 minutes.</description></item></channel></rss>