<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>side on The Open Source Cookbook</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/categories/side/</link><description>Recent content in side on The Open Source Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/categories/side/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dill Pickles</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/dill-pickles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/dill-pickles/</guid><description>Equipment Chef&amp;rsquo;s knife Cutting board 2 wide-mouth pint jars with lids Large pot, if canning Ingredients 1 1/2 pounds Kirby or Persian cucumbers 4 cloves garlic, peeled and smashed 2 teaspoons dill seeds 1/2 teaspoon red pepper flakes (optional) 1 cup apple cider vinegar (or white vinegar) 1 cup water 1 1/2 tablespoons pickling salt or kosher salt Directions Prepare the jars. If you are planning to can your pickles for long-term storage, bring a large pot of water to a boil and sterilize 2 wide-mouth pint jars and their lids.</description></item><item><title>Corn Bread</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/corn-bread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/corn-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup of cornmeal 3/4 cup of all-purpose flour 2-4 tablespoons of sugar 2 1/2 teaspoons of baking powder 1/2 teaspoon of salt 1 cup of milk 2 eggs 1/4 cup of butter, melted Directions Preheat oven to 400°F. Grease an 8x8x2-inch square or 9x1 1/2-inch round baking pan; set aside. In a medium bowl stir together cornmeal, flour, sugar, baking powder, and salt; set aside. In a small bowl whisk together the milk, eggs, and butter.</description></item><item><title>Guacamole</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/guacamole/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 avocados - peeled, pitted, and mashed 1 lime, juiced 1 teaspoon salt 1/2 cup diced onion 3 tablespoons chopped fresh cilantro 2 roma (plum) tomatoes, diced 1 teaspoon minced garlic 1 pinch ground cayenne pepper Directions In a medium bowl, mash together the avocados, lime juice, and salt. Mix in onion, cilantro, tomatoes, and garlic. Stir in cayenne pepper. Refrigerate 1 hour for best flavor, or serve immediately.</description></item></channel></rss>