<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sauce on The Open Source Cookbook</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/categories/sauce/</link><description>Recent content in sauce on The Open Source Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/categories/sauce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Steak Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/steak-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/steak-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients Try with Tamarind 1 1/4 cups ketchup 2 tablespoons prepared yellow mustard 3 tablespoons Worcestershire sauce 1 1/2 tablespoons apple cider vinegar 4 drops hot pepper sauce (e.g. Tabasco) 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper Directions In a medium bowl, mix together the ketchup, mustard, Worcestershire sauce, vinegar, hot pepper sauce, salt and pepper. Transfer to a jar and refrigerate until needed.</description></item><item><title>Easy Pizza Sauce I</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-pizza-sauce-i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/easy-pizza-sauce-i/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (6 ounce) can tomato paste 1 1/2 cups water 1/3 cup extra virgin olive oil 2 cloves garlic, minced salt to taste ground black pepper to taste 1/2 tablespoon dried oregano 1/2 tablespoon dried basil 1/2 teaspoon dried rosemary, crushed Directions Mix together the tomato paste, water, and olive oil. Mix well. Add garlic, salt and pepper to taste, oregano, basil, and rosemary. Mix well and let stand several hours to let flavors blend.</description></item><item><title>Homemade Hoisin Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/homemade-hoisin-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/homemade-hoisin-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/4 cup soy sauce 2 tablespoons smooth peanut butter 1 tablespoon dark brown sugar 2 teaspoons rice wine vinegar 2 teaspoons sesame oil 1 teaspoon hot sauce, or to taste 1 clove garlic, minced 1/8 teaspoon ground black pepper Directions Whisk soy sauce, peanut butter, brown sugar, rice wine vinegar, sesame oil, hot sauce, garlic, and black pepper together in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Dipping Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/peanut-dipping-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/peanut-dipping-sauce/</guid><description>My family goes nuts for this peanut sauce. Pun intended. It is probably the strong driver of Asian inspired meals in my home.
Ingredients 3/4 cup creamy peanut butter 1/4 cup rice vinegar 1/3 cup reduced sodium tamari or reduced-sodium soy sauce 3 tablespoons honey 1 1/2 teaspoons grated fresh ginger or 1/2 teaspoon ground ginger 1 to 2 medium cloves garlic, pressed or minced, to taste 1/4 teaspoon red pepper flakes, plus more for sprinkling 2 to 4 tablespoons water or coconut milk, or as necessary to reach your desired consistency Optional garnishes: sprinkling of chopped roasted peanuts and additional red pepper flakes Directions In a 2-cup liquid measuring cup or medium-sized mixing bowl, whisk together the ingredients until well blended.</description></item><item><title>Worchestershire Sauce</title><link>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/worchestershire-sauce/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://trev-dev.github.io/cookbook/recipe/worchestershire-sauce/</guid><description>Need a solution for seasoning red meat that won&amp;rsquo;t hurt a celiac person? Look no further than here.
Ingredients 1/2 cup apple cider vinegar 2 Tbsp GF soy sauce 2 Tbsp water 1 Tbsp brown sugar 1/4 tsp ground ginger 1/4 tsp dry mustard 1/4 tsp onion powder 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1/8 tsp cinnamon 1/8 tsp pepper Directions Place all ingredients in a medium saucepan and stir. Bring to a boil, stirring constantly.</description></item></channel></rss>